all right
[Music]
Hippocrates said all diseases begin in
the gut previously I've talked about
fecal transplants transferring the stool
of healthy people into the colons of
patients suffering from inflammatory
bowel disease multiple sclerosis even
psychiatric problems like depression
bipolar disorder and alcoholism to
repopulate their gut with good bacteria
in hopes of improving their conditions
what about fecal transplants for aging
might the Fountain of Youth be a
fountain of poop
if you give mice with accelerated aging
a fecal transplant from healthy mice
they perk up and live longer but what
about human poop we don't yet have human
to human aging data but we do have mice
transplanted with fecal matter from a
centenarian mice fed poop from 101 year
old versus poop from a 70 year old
lipofusiness age pigment that's widely
used as a biomarker for aging and
lipofus and accumulates significantly
Less in the brain tissue of centenarian
poop fed mice raising the possibility
that we will one day be using
centenarian fecal matter for anti-aging
purposes and to promote healthy aging
why bathe in the blood of virgins when
you can dine on the dung of the
venerable
to be continued once human to human data
are published poop you may want to avoid
is from overweight stool donors given
this case report about weight gain after
a fecal transplant 32 year old woman had
always been of normal weight until she
received a fecal transplant from a
healthy but overweight donor her
daughter after the transplant she became
obese gaining more than 40 pounds she
said she felt like there was a switch
inside her body her gastroenterologist
reported no matter how much she ate or
exercise she couldn't take the weight
off she was very frustrated the same
thing happens in mice giving mice fecal
pellets from an obese Mouse resulted in
nearly a doubling in fat Mass compared
to lean Mouse pellets despite eating
significantly fewer calories this proves
gut Flora can play a pivotal role in
obesity
in mice what about in people researchers
decided to study pairs of human twins
discordant for obesity meaning one twin
was fat the other skinny what would
happen if you switched their microbiomes
the siblings may have been squeamish so
the researchers reverted to mice again
mice fed stool from the obese twin
rapidly swelled in size but not those
fed from the lean twin despite
comparable calorie intakes
co-housing the mice together prevented
the weight gain however the lean type
bacteria jumped over to rescue the
mouse-fed stool from the obese twin but
and here's the critical point only in
the context of a healthier diet the
microbial cure only worked when the mice
were fed low saturated fat high fiber
diets which makes sense since the lean
type bacteria appeared to be fiber
feeders together the researchers
concluded these results illustrate how a
diet high in saturated fats and low in
fruits and vegetables can select against
human gut bacteria associated with
leanness the results of the twins face
suggest that the role of our gut floor
in obesity is just to help take Fuller
advantage of a more healthful diet so if
the twins had actually swapped their
stool the obese twin might have only
lost weight if they combine the
microbial makeover with healthier eating
to Aid the colonization of the better
bugs with the new bacteria on board
though the healthier diet could have
resulted in more weight loss even eating
the same number of calories but you
don't really know until you put it to
the test there have been previous
published attempts randomized double
blind placebo-controlled trial showing
no weight loss benefit to getting lean
donor fecal transplants but they kept
people on the same crappy diets that led
to obesity in the first place who cares
if you keep putting slimming fiber
feeding bacteria into your gut if you
don't give them any fiber to eat they'll
just starve and die right off so maybe
you have to do both pairing gut bacteria
modulation with a dietary intervention
but if you do a plant-based diet along
with a transplant and they lose a bunch
of weight how do you know if the
transplant had anything to do with it
which brings us to this study what they
did is put people on a healthy
plant-based diet supplemented with green
tea and green smoothies until they lost
about 20 pounds over six months and
grabbed a fecal sample then they were
randomized to spend the rest of the year
constantly seeding their gut with a
healthy microbiome they had achieved at
maximum weight loss or to Placebo
capsules the question was once they go
back to their regular diets were those
getting the constant infusion of their
own skinny poop help them keep the
weight off
yes they found that participants who
lost weight on a healthy diet and were
then fed capsules containing fecal
matter collected during the diet period
for months after the maximal weight loss
regained less weight than participants
given Placebo capsules so the
plant-based diet appeared to produce the
optimal fecal microbiome for preventing
weight regain but rather than eating
your own plant-based poo why not just
stick with the plant-based diet
laughs
thank you